{
    "question": "Contoh simple present tense, verbal dan nominal",
    "attachments": [],
    "answers": [
        {
            "answer": "Simple Present Tense : Subject + V1 + keterangan waktu yang biasa dilakukan.ex : usually, every, always, often, sometimes,once, a week, a twice, etc.<br>Contohnya : he runs very quickly",
            "attachments": []
        }
    ],
    "related_questions": [
        {
            "slug": "terjemahan-teks-the-spying-parrot-892",
            "question": "Terjemahan teks the spying parrot",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "Ini terjemahannnya<br>Mata-Mata burung beo <br>",
                    "attachments": []
                },
                {
                    "answer": "mata-mata burung beo",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "contoh-kalimat-past-tense-menggunakan-used-to-712",
            "question": "Contoh kalimat past tense menggunakan used to",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "that scissors used my mom<br>",
                    "attachments": []
                },
                {
                    "answer": "contohnya : i used to studying at night<br><br>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "change-into-the-correct-simple-present-or-simple-past-form-1-i-897",
            "question": "change into the correct simple present or simple past form 1. I.....(live) right off an alleyway blablabla.. 2. It....(be) the alleyway behind blabla.. 3. this....(need) to be paid attention immediately and 4. ...... (require)immediate repairing. 5. blabla.. last night it ..... (rain) for maybe an hour, and look what it 6. ...... (do). 7. some of the potholes ..... (be) 5 inches deep. 8. please I .... (beg) you, blabla.. 9. we .... (need) the road resurfaced.\u00a0 10. it....(look) like a thrid world country outside my house. \u00a0 \u00a0 1. every day I .... (pass) rotan street to go to my office which it situated on burton street and 2. ..... (return) home the same route. this has been a routin for twelve years. but last week, to my dismay, I 3. .... (have) to go around to the other way when I 4. ...(return) home from my office. as I was going to turn to Rotan street, there 15. .... (be) a sign that all street users to rotan sreet 16. ... (can) enter it that day because one of the residentswas having a weeding party. 17. .... (have) to turn my car to pasadena street and I was trapped in a trafic jam half an hour. it 18. .... (be) a nuisance. I ..... (reach) home late in the evening. I think that streets 20..... (be) \u00a0for public use. it should not be use for private use. if you 21. ....(hold) a weeding party, you should rent a weeding hall or a meeting hall in the near sub district. streets 22 .... (be) for trafic, it \u00a023. .... (be) not for private party.",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "1. lived<br>2.was<br>3.needed<br>4.required<br>5.rained<br>6.did<br>7.were<br>8.begged<br>9.needed<br>10.looked",
                    "attachments": []
                },
                {
                    "answer": "<span>\n                change into the correct simple present or simple past form\n1.\n                <span>change into the correct simple present or simple past form\n<br>1. I..LIVE...(live) right off an alleyway blablabla..\n<br>2. It...IS...(be) the alleyway behind blabla..\n<br>3. this..NEEDS..(need) to be paid attention immediately and <br>4. ..REQUIRES.... (require)immediate repairing.\n<br>5. blabla.. last night it ..RAINED... (rain) for maybe an hour, and look what it <br>6. ...DOES... (do).\n<br>7. some of the potholes ..ARE... (be) 5 inches deep.\n<br>8. please I .BEG... (beg) you, blabla..\n<br>9. we ..NEED.. (need) the road resurfaced.\u00a0\n<br>10. it..LOOKS..(look) like a thrid world country outside my house.\n\u00a0\n\u00a0\n<span><br><br>1. every day I ..PASS.. (pass) rotan street to go to my office which it \nsituated on burton street and 2. .RETURN.... (return) home the same route. \nthis has been a routin for twelve years. but last week, to my dismay, I \n3. HAD.... (have) to go around to the other way when I 4. .RETURNED..(return) home \nfrom my office. as I was going to turn to Rotan street, there 15. .WAS... \n(be) a sign that all street users to rotan sreet 16. ..COULDN&#039;T. (can) enter it \nthat day because one of the residents was having a weeding party. 17. \n.I HAD... (have) to turn my car to pasadena street and I was trapped in a \ntrafic jam half an hour. it 18. .WAS... (be) a nuisance. I ..REACHED... (reach) \nhome late in the evening. I think that streets 20...ARE.. (be) \u00a0for public \nuse. it should not be use for private use. if you 21. WILL HOLD....(hold) a \nweeding party, you should rent a weeding hall or a meeting hall in the \nnear sub district. streets 22 .ARE... (be) for trafic, it \u00a023. IS.... (be) \nnot for private party.</span></span>\n            </span><br>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "ada-yang-tau-contoh-berita-acara-serah-terima-pekerjaan-proyek-558",
            "question": "Ada yang tau contoh Berita Acara Serah Terima Pekerjaan (Proyek) dalam bahasa Inggris?",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<span><em>Handover Works (Project</em><span><em>)</em></span></span><br><br>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "buatkan-teks-horatory-tentang-menanam-pohon-586",
            "question": "Buatkan teks horatory tentang menanam pohon\u00a0",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "Horatori : tema : argumentasi : saran<br><br>Planting a tree is one of the effort that we can do to make a better air quality. This is due to the ability of tree and its leaves in transforming carbon dioxide into oxygen. Therefore it is highly recommended to start plant a tree at least in our backyard.\u00a0",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "contoh-recount-teks-tentang-stady-tour-di-jakarta-245",
            "question": "Contoh recount teks tentang stady tour di jakarta",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "Saya hanya memberikan langkah pentingnya saja. Sebenarnya mudah untuk membuat recoun text. Topiknya kan, tentang study tour, coba cari informasi sejelas-jelasnya tentang study tour. Lalu, kembangkan menjadi sebuah recount teks. Pakai bahasa indonesia dulu. Setelah ditata rapi dengan bahasa indonesia yang baik dan literer, diubah ke dalam bahasa inggris. Okay ? @Liwed",
                    "attachments": []
                },
                {
                    "answer": "Aku kasih caranya aja ya. Pertama rangkai kejadian study tour kamu dari awal sampai akhir kemudian translate kan ke bahasa inggris, karena inti dari recount text itu menulis dan mengarang kejadian yang memang pernah terjadi dan kita alami<br>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "bisa-gak-buatin-pidato-dari-teks-ini-plastic-surgery-is-not-s-r-624",
            "question": "Bisa gak buatin pidato dari teks ini\u00a0    plastic surgery is not s recent phenimenon, but it was appeared since 3000 years ago. in the past, it was for medical purpose but now it is creating beuty and trend to modify some part of body.\r\nmany people nowaday want to be extraordinary such as animal or less human by plastic surgery. they modifying their faces and bodies to make them more animal like. meny so called 'lizard people' have had their tongues split. a woman who changed her face like a cat. other people gone beyond different kinds of tattoos.\r\nthe people who done outcast actually they lack self respect and have adesperate need for attention. they should be treated by psychiatrist, not plastic surgeons. and we should be aware of society that no longer wants to look human",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "hi people, today i will tell you about plastic surgery. plastic surgery appeared 3000 years ago, in the past, it was for medical purpose but now it is only for a change of appearance. many people nowdays want to have a beautiful or handsome face, in other words &#039;being closer to perfections in the matter of appearance&#039;. but some people have some really weird tastes and they tried to be less human-like, by using plastic surgery, they tried to looks like a lizard or cats, and many other animals. the people that took plastic surgery is usually people who is not satisfied with their looks, or their body. they degraded\u00a0the gods creation, and try to be more &#039;perfect&#039;, however they sometime did not look at the risk. you see, if the surgery failed, then can you even imagine what your body or face would look like? and because of that i highly recommend not to take plastic surgery, and appreciate what god has given to us.\u00a0\u00a0<br><br>^aku tambahin beberapa informasi\u00a0",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "terdiri-dari-apa-sajakah-causative-have-itu-798",
            "question": "Terdiri dari apa sajakah causative have itu",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "Causative verb menunjukkan bahwa seseorang/sesuatu secara tidak langsung bertanggung jawab terhadap sebuah tindakan. Subjek tidak melakukan tindakan itu sendiri, tetapi justru menyebabkan seseorang/sesuatu yang lain melakukannya. Contoh:<br>- Yesterday I had my hair cut.<br>Pembicara pada kalimat diatas tidak memotong sendiri rambutnya, tetapi justru membuat orang lain melakukannya \u2013 Saya \u201cmenyebabkan\u201d mereka memotong rambut saya.<br>Have<br>Have merupakan causative verb yang umum. Ketimbang melakukan sesuatu dengan diri kita sendiri, kita \u201cmenyuruh\u201d orang yang lain untuk melakukannya. Bentuknya sebagai berikut:<br>Kata kerja \u201cto have\u201d + objek + past participle (verb 3). Contoh:<br>- I had my jacket cleaned yesterday.<br>- Did you have your computer fixed?<br>Terkadang kita menggunakan have sebagai causative verb ketika kita ingin melakukan tindakan oleh diri kita sendiri. Contoh:<br>- When will the report be ready? I\u2019ll do it by tomorrow morning. &gt;&gt;<br>- When will the report be ready? I\u2019ll have it done by tomorrow morning.<br>Dengan menggunakan causative, kalimat ke-dua diatas mengalihkan perhatian dari pelaku tindakan, dan lebih memberikan perhatian kepada tindakan yang sedang dilakukan. Ini kedengaran sopan dan profesional.<br>Get<br>Get sering digunakan ketimbang have. Contoh:<br>\u2022\tI got my computer fixed \u2013 I had my computer fixed. Kedua kalimat ini maknanya sama.<br>\u2022\tI got my jacket cleaned. \u2013 I had my jacket cleaned. Kedua kalimat ini maknanya sama.<br>Causative verbs sering digunakan bersama dengan pengalaman-pengalaman negatif. Pada situasi-situasi ini lebih umum menggunakan have. Contoh:<br>\u2022\tI had my wallet stolen. (Saya sebenarnya tidak menyebabkan dompet saya dicuri \u2013 seseorang mencuri dompet saya dariku)<br><span>\u2022\tShe had her window smashed.<br><br></span>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "tolong-describe-dengan-tema-my-beloved-home-386",
            "question": "Tolong describe dengan tema \"my beloved home\"",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "My beloved home<br><br>It is located in the central park. My home is the sweetest home on my complex. It has green roof which is made from special clay. Therefore it is always shining when the sun light rise in the morning.\u00a0",
                    "attachments": []
                },
                {
                    "answer": "my home.. my everything.. even\u00a0my home not as huge the president home or a museums.. even my home don&#039;t as rich as the businessman home.. i love my home.. because my home protect me from the light of the sun , from the extreme weather , from the cold of the rain.. but i still love my home..home sweet home.. you&#039;re my protecter from childhood.. how bad you&#039;re you still my home... i called it my beloved home",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "tolong-describe-dengan-tema-my-beloved-home-523",
            "question": "Tolong describe dengan tema \"my beloved home\"",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "I live in an ordinary house, but I always feel that I belong here for no reason. My house really cozy, it has 4 rooms with AC inside, 1 kitchen, 3 bathrooms, 1 livingrooms, and a green garden in front of it. My mom always take care of this house. I think it&#039;s right that our house is our palace because we can do what we want no matter what. Two years ago, I almost moved to the other house because there was an accident, and sssttt I can&#039;t tell you, because it&#039;s secret. So I think that&#039;s all",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}